yankeecandlefundraising.com 2010-10-06

# Yankee Candle Fund-Raising: Privacy and Security

Thank you for visiting www.yankeecandlefundraising.com. Yankee Candle is committed to honoring and protecting your privacy while at the same time providing you with a first rate on-line and shopping experience. As an important part of respecting your privacy, we believe that you have the right to know what information is collected by this Web site, how such information may be used, and what security measures are taken to protect your information.

When you visit our Web site, place an order, request a catalog and/or contact us via e-mail, certain information is or may be collected. Among the types of information that may be collected are the following:   

  * domain names of visitors to our site; 
  * if you place an order or contact us, your name, address, e-mail address and whatever credit card information you provide in connection with your purchase; 
  * "navigational information" regarding the traffic patterns of our Web site, including the number of visits to a particular page and user-specific information on which pages a guest visits, average length of time spent on the site and similar site usage data; and 
  * any information that you may choose to submit in connection with any e-mail messages, on-site surveys, registry programs, contests and the like. 

We use this information in order to analyze, manage and improve our Web site so that we may continually strive to provide you with the best shopping experience that we possibly can. Information on traffic patterns and the number of page visits and the like helps us to further develop and improve our site layout to better meet your needs. Of course, we also use information such as your name, e-mail address and credit card information to contact you, respond to your inquiries, send you a catalog and to process, deliver and receive payment for your purchases. We may use such information to notify you of services, special offers, new products and other services that we believe may be of interest to you, or to notify you of important new changes in our Web site. Finally, we use collected information to help us diagnose problems with our server or other technical issues relating to the performance of the Web site.

"Cookies" are small bits of data that a web site can send to your browser and may then be stored on your hard drive. We use cookies in connection with certain features on our Web site, although we note that our cookies do not contain any personally identifying information such as your name. We use the cookies to enable us to store items in your shopping cart and may also use them to help provide you with customized or tailored information or services. You can set your web browser so that you will always be notified when you receive a cookie.

Yankee Candle makes every effort to protect the security of your personal information. Our Web site is hosted on secure servers and utilizes SSL secure server software. Any personal information that you provide is encrypted so that no-one can read it while it is being transmitted over the Internet. Any information collected by us is stored in private files behind a firewall designed to protect your information by denying unauthorized access by outside users.

If you do not wish to receive e-mail regarding special offers, or catalogs, please let us know by sending us an e-mail to info@yankeecandle.com. Please be sure that your e-mail includes your name and address. If you are requesting to be removed from our mailing list, please include the source code that is located on the back of your catalog.

You can also let us know by mailing us c/o The Yankee Candle Company, Inc., Internet and Catalog Sales, P.O. Box 110, South Deerfield, MA 01373-0110, or by calling us at 1-877-803-6890.

If you would like to correct or update any information that you have previously provided, you may do so via e-mail to [info@yankeecandle.com](mailto:info@yankeecandle.com), or by mail or phone call as set forth above. 

Please note that sometimes these requests may take up to 6-8 weeks to be effective, particularly if we are removing your name from postal mailings. In addition, when you purchase from us online or through our catalogs, or when you choose to enter a sweepstakes or other promotion, we may need to contact you via phone, email or mail to address questions or issues specific to your order, entry, etc., even if you have opted to not receive communications.

To serve you better, we may combine information you give us online, in our stores or through our catalogs. We may also combine that information with publicly available information and information we receive from or cross-reference with our Select Partners and others. We use that combined information to enhance and personalize your shopping experience with us, to communicate with you about our products and events that may be of interest to you, and for other promotional purposes.

Our mailing lists are sometimes made available to companies whose products and services may be of interest to you. 

We may collect, store or accumulate certain non-personally identifiable information concerning your use of this Website, such as information regarding which of our pages are most popular. We may share or transfer such non-personally identifiable information with or to our affiliates, licensees and partners. We may disclose any information, including personally identifiable information, we deem necessary, in our sole discretion, to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or governmental request.

We may contract with companies or persons to provide certain services including credit card processing, shipping, data management, promotional services, etc. We call them our Service Providers. We provide our Service Providers with the information needed for them to perform these services. We also ask our Service Providers to confirm that their privacy practices are consistent with ours.

Although unlikely, in certain instances we may disclose your personally identifiable information when we have reason to believe that it is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against persons or entities who may be causing injury to you, to Yankee Candle Company, Inc. or to others. We may also disclose your personally identifiable information when we believe the law requires it. 

When you visit this Website or view one of our e-mails, we may use pixel tags (also called "clear" gifs), tracking links and/or similar technology to note some of the pages you visit on our Website and personalize your experience. We may also use pixel tags to determine what types of e-mail your browser supports. We may use the information collected through pixel tags, tracking links and similar technology in combination with your personally identifiable information.

We may use the information you provide in aggregate form for internal business purposes, such as generating statistics and developing marketing plans. We will not sell or rent your personally identifiable information to third parties without your consent, except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy.

As we continue to develop our business, we might sell certain of our assets. In such transactions, user information, including personally identifiable information, generally is one of the transferred business assets, and by submitting your personal information on the Website you agree that your data may be transferred to such parties in these circumstances.

We may revise this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we decide to change our Privacy Policy, we will post the revised policy here. As we may make changes at any time without notifying you, we suggest that you periodically consult this Privacy Policy. Please note that our rights to use your personally identifiable information will be based on the privacy policy in effect at the time the information is used.

When you complete a feedback form or one of our surveys, you may opt-out of receiving future communications from us. You may change your preferences at any time by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of each e-mail you receive from us or by e-mailing us at [info@yankeecandle.com](mailto:info@yankeecandle.com). You may remove your name from our mailing list by calling 1-877-803-6890.
